Off the map, things get strange.
Encounters at the End of the World is a
documentary film directed by Werner Herzog.
Herzog and cinematographer Peter Zeitlinger go to Antarctica to meet people who live and
work there, and to capture footage of the continent's unique locations.
Herzog's voiceover narration explains that his film will not be a typical Antarctica film about
"fluffy penguins", but will explore the dreams of the people and the landscape.
Narrator (voice), played by Werner Herzog.
Self - Volcanologist, played by Clive Oppenheimer.
Self - Transportation Dept, played by Scott Rowland.
Self - Philosopher, Forklift Driver, played by Stefan Pashov.
Self - Glaciologist, played by Doug MacAyeal.
Self - Filmmaker, Cook, played by Ryan Andrew Evans.
Encounters at the End of the World is a 2007 American documentary film by Werner
Herzog about Antarctica and the people who choose to spend time there.
It was released in North America on June 11, 2008, and distributed by ThinkFilm.
At the 81st Academy Awards, the film was nominated for Best Documentary Feature.
The film explores themes of marine biologist,
penguin, iceberg, volcano, wilderness.